<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts &amp; Ideas</title>
    <description>Mostly university work, design and programming
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 19:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 19:09:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>International Pedagogy: How far? 📍</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;brief&quot;&gt;Brief&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;International Pedagogy was the first challenge I was given in my Research and Communication class. The challenge is to edit and present to members of our new cohort with simple phrases and/or actions and information to teach them about what “you” think they need to know about where you are from. The presentation should not be seen from a tourist perspective but a personal perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brief has a paragraph stating “key words and phrases, cultural considerations, etiquette and how to be streetwise”. I started my work by looking at the paragraph and listing all the possible ways I could go with my presentation. I picked each theme and made a list of what I could explore using that theme. I called my mum and asked her to tell me things only Nigerians can relate to. I texted my friends and asked them about it. And my personal experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;words-and-phrases&quot;&gt;Words and Phrases&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I dive into this theme I need to give background knowledge about Nigerian Pidgin Language. Pidgin language is a language that has developed from a mixture of two languages. It is used as a way of communicating by people who do not speak each other’s languages (Pidgin, n.d). Nigerian Pidgin is an English based pidgin language spoken in every part of Nigeria, it is sort of a lingua franca in Nigeria. Nigerian Pidgin is used in informal conversations. Nigerian Pidgin is so popular Google Search has an interface for it and a lot of News outlets like BBC also do their news in the slang. An example of Nigerian Pidgin is “I Dey” which means “I’m alright” in English. The brief has a paragraph stating “key words and phrases, cultural considerations, etiquette and how to be streetwise”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most popular phrase in Nigerian Pidgin is “How far?”. “How far?” has different meanings depending on the context. In most contexts, it is a simple informal greeting that’s best used with people you know. It means “How is everything”, if someone asks you “How far?” in Nigeria they are not referring to your journey to meet them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are many other Nigerian Pidgins but I cannot go through of all of them because there is as many words or phrases as a dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cultural-considerations&quot;&gt;Cultural Considerations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The northern part of Nigeria is heavily influenced by Islam. The cultural considerations follow mostly Islamic /Arab culture. Where women and women are separated in social activities unless they are siblings or married.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wedding Fatiha [Daurin Aure]&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Wedding from where I come from is a whole week event starting with a wedding Fatiha(Islamic marriage) and ending with the main wedding reception.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Here are the lists of events that take place in order:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Kayan Lefe
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The grooms’ side of the family shop for the bride. The items include but are not limited to shoes, bags, clothes, underwear, perfumes, cash, etc&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wedding Fatiha [Daurin Aure]
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This is the most significant part of the wedding. A religious priest is invited to make the wedding official. The event takes place at the mosque or brides house with guests invited. As opposed to what obtains in many other cultures, in the Hausa culture it is a representative from the groom and bride’s family usually does the exchange of vows and not the bride and groom.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wuni [Sa lalle]
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This is event is strictly for ladies, the brides family, friends and the grooms family. The event takes place in the brides family home. A mixture of traditional henna is made and used to make beautiful designs on the brides’ palms, hands and feet. Friends and families get henna designs on their bodies also.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Kamun Amariya
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;It is a playful event where the grooms family goes to the brides family home to convince and negotiate with them to allow them to take their daughter, thus making her part of the grooms family.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Kai Amariya
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This is where family and friends escort the bride to her matrimonial home, to be well received by the groom’s family. It is followed by prayers and advice from family and friends. It ends with entertainment, food and music for the family and guest.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;etiquette&quot;&gt;Etiquette&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nigerian etiquette is different from western etiquette, some westerners might call it absurd. To compile the list for my presentation I had to research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Physical/Body Contact&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;In this part of the world called Nigeria physical contact is seen as a very normal activity, for example when someone is trying to call your name, get your attention or simply when having a conversation they can touch you. To outsiders, they’ll find this odd because of the invasion of personal space.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Greeting&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Exchange of greeting cannot be rushed, it is seen as rude behaviour. You must take the time to ask about the person’s health, the health of their family, or other social niceties. That sounds quite normal but the problem is if you see the same person the next day you have to do it all over again. Also when greeting someone much older, it is a sign of respect and deference to bow the head.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Age&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Old age in Nigeria is an accomplishment. Old people are given utmost respect and cannot be disrespected in any way even if they are wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Left Hand is a Taboo&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Avoid greeting, giving or receiving objects or handling money or food with your left hand. It is seen as disrespectful and disgusting to greet, eat, handover or collect things from others with a left hand.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Time&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;There is a concept of time called “Nigerian Time” which is a concept where things rarely start on time, appointments are not usually made, interruptions are frequent, and one can expect to wait for things to happen. When someone tells you an event is starting at 7 pm it means it’ll start at 9 pm or 10 pm. And also it is a way of showing high standards by making the person wait.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;presentation&quot;&gt;Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I titled my presentation “How Far?” to draw the attention of my audience by telling them I’ll explain the meaning of the title at the end of the presentation. I did that to hold the listeners attention. For the presentation since none of my listeners are from where I come from, I tried to focus on the things that are completely normal in Nigeria but are absurd to people from not that part of the world. I re-edited my research and created a 5 minutes presentation, you can find &lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.cambridge.org/&quot;&gt;Dictionary.cambridge.org&lt;/a&gt;. (2019). PIDGIN  meaning in the Cambridge English Dictionary. [online] Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://dictionary.cambridge.org/dictionary/english/pidgin&quot;&gt;https://dictionary.cambridge.org/dictionary/english/pidgin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 05:43:48 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/International-Pedagogy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/International-Pedagogy</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Cut: Airline Companies &amp; Plastic 🛫</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;brief&quot;&gt;Brief&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are required to record and present your group impressions of a London Event visit (researched and negotiated prior to attendance. Design and design related events can be found in abundance in London and surrounding areas. After careful negotiation, discussion and agreed consensus, you will edit and assemble a 10-minute presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following from my last &lt;strong&gt;post&lt;/strong&gt;, I was tasked with researching and editing slides for our presentation about the challenges about why airline companies haven’t switched to a sustainable replacement to plastics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a student the first thing I did was to open to &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com&quot;&gt;google.com&lt;/a&gt; and search for my query, that was the beginning of my research.  I went through several sites to gather my results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;findings&quot;&gt;Findings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/plasticwaste.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Plastic Waste&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 1 Plastic Waste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the findings from the research:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Low cost of producing plastics is the major reason(It is cheap)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plastics are lighter than the alternatives available(steel or ceramics) thus reducing fuel consumption&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Items need to be packaged to some extent and packaging alternative is more costly at this point&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is currently no tested and used eco-friendly replacement for plastic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is easier for personnel to inspect items like blankets and headsets for signs of tampering&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not all plastics are produced equal. Their likelihood of being replaced boils down to their resin identification code.(Tiny triangles with the number inside that indicates the type of plastic an item is made of)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most companies use it as a way to differentiate service between economy class to the expensive classes(Business and First class)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It keeps collecting, washing and sanitising dish-ware to a minimum.(Saves cost for companies)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results from the research always comes back to the fact airline companies only care about saving cost and maximising profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Malik, J. (2019). Basically everything you’re given on an airplane is wrapped in plastic. That’s a huge environmental problem.. [online] Vox. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/7/9/20680969/airplanes-plastic-zero-waste-flights&quot;&gt;https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/7/9/20680969/airplanes-plastic-zero-waste-flights&lt;/a&gt; [Accessed 7 Nov. 2019].&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pepper, F. (2018). ‘Everything gets destroyed’: The difficult problem of plane passenger waste. [online] ABC News. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abc.net.au/news/2018-08-21/plastic-waste-created-in-plane-cabin-no-easy-solution/10117576&quot;&gt;https://www.abc.net.au/news/2018-08-21/plastic-waste-created-in-plane-cabin-no-easy-solution/10117576&lt;/a&gt; [Accessed 22 Oct. 2019].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 05:43:48 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/First-Cut-Research</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/First-Cut-Research</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Cut: Idea 💡</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;brief&quot;&gt;Brief&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brief was given in my Research and Communication class at University to work in a group titled “First Cut” of visiting a design event in London researched and negotiated before attending. This was the first assignment given to be us to be done as a group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-a-group&quot;&gt;Finding a Group&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is we were all new at the time the brief was given I was only talking to 2 other classmates of mine. The &lt;strong&gt;CHALLENGE&lt;/strong&gt; was to get into a group of 3 or more and work on the assignment. At first, it was a daunting task for me, how am I going to get into a group?. Throughout the week I thought should I ask one of them if there are already in a group or lest create one. So during the next class during the break I went to meet one and asked her if she has a group, she was like yes do you want to join? I said yes as simple as that I got into a group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meet-up-and-ideas&quot;&gt;Meet Up and Ideas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/firstidea.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Discussion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 1 Discussion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That same day we agreed to meet at the library to discuss how we are going to approach the assignment(see Fig. 2). After the days’ lesson, we all went to the library met up and discussed, research and negotiated together which London design event we are to going and how we were going to breakdown the assignment. We all sat down and started exchanging and floating ideas on how to go about with the assignment, I was shocked by the number of ideas floating around. We all had our strong points, Joko is good in taking initiative, Antonie is good in analysis, and the rest of us were good at creative thinking. Very captivating and intellectual ideas were being exchanged and being noted. One person was writing all the ideas being thrown during brainstorming stage. We as a collective decided to go to London Design museum because they were having an exhibition about plastic waste generated when traveling titled “ PriestmanGoode presents Get Onboard: Reduce. Reuse. Rethink “ it was an idea we all in the group relate, understand and a big problem in the world right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition was reiterated and explored deeper to see how we can utilise it. The main idea we had is to educate people about the amount of waste they generate per day without having a second thought about it. And also small action can make a big difference. We decided to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A short film documenting the waste we produced for the trip.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Produce a stop motion video for the waste.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One member of the group suggested our presentation follows a method, the method involves splitting the presentation into introduction, research, challenge and solution. The tasks were shared depending on the person’s preference and skills.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 05:43:48 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/First-Cut-Idea</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/First-Cut-Idea</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Good and Poor Design using Dieter Rams Principles for Good Design 📐</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;brief&quot;&gt;Brief&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my Research and Communication class, I was tasked with discussing 3 good and 3 poor designs  using the 10 Principles for Good Design by Dieter Rams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to understand why good design is important. Design is a form of communication, communication is meant to be clear and easy to understand. The same applies to good design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is good design? That is where Dieter Rams takes control. Dieter Rams is a German Industrial Designer known for his “less is better” philosophy which he used to design several products for Braun. He led and laid guidelines for the Functionalist design movement. Functionalist design is a design movement in which the form of the object is driven by the purpose of the object and not by its aesthetics only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by examining the products around me that I use daily and compared them to the Good Design Principles. I created a list of the products and further drilled them down to the ones that interested me the most to expand upon(I think they are good examples).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dieter Rams codified his learning experience as a Designer into a set of 10 collective principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-10-principles-for-good-design&quot;&gt;The 10 Principles for Good Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Dieter Rams, good design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is innovative&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Makes a product useful&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is aesthetic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Makes a product understandable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is unobtrusive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is honest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is long lasting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is thorough down to the last detail&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is environmentally friendly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is as little design as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;good-design&quot;&gt;Good Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tote Bag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people use the tote bag as an eco-friendly replacement for plastics when they go shopping or to store food in their pantries. Others wear it as a fashion accessory that meets and exceeds all expectations of comfort and aesthetics. The tote bag is now a universal symbol of functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It ticks all the 10 Good Design Principles by Dieter Rams. A tote bag(see Fig. 1) design is simple and allows the user to use it in any way or form. The user can hold it, put on it on their shoulder or strap it around which makes unobtrusive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/tote.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a tote bag&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 1 A Tote Bag&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Polaroid Camera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edwin Land invented the instant film in 1947. The Polaroid design(see Fig. 2) is an iconic design that is still being used in Point and Shoot Camera. The shutter button is so easy to handle a toddler can play with a polaroid camera. The only function is to shoot and print photos with few or none filter presets. The company is still producing camera’s with the initial design of the camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Dieter Rams Principle for Design, the Polaroid Camera design was innovative, the first of its kind. It is aesthetically  pleasing and easily strikes all the criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/polaroid.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a polaroid camera&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 2 A Polaroid Camera&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one a lot of people fail to appreciate because of how it is everywhere. The ease and delight of squeezing ketchup out of plastic bottle compare to the glass bottle is hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swiss Army Knife&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Schweiser Officersmesser know as the Swiss Army Knife was designed for the Swiss Army by West &amp;amp; Co in 1890. The Swiss Army knife was originally designed for an army but it continues to be used for various reasons by everyday people. What makes the Swiss army knife so great is its ability to contain multiple tools while remaining compact. This makes it easy for people to carry it around anywhere and put it to use when they see fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Swiss Army Knife follows Dieter Rams’ Principles for design. The Swiss Army Knife design is long-lasting, it continues to be utilised by people today. The Swiss Army Knife is also an extremely useful product, there are multiple variations of the tool combinations for the purpose of suiting individual users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/swissknife.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a swiss knife&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 3 A Swiss Knife&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;poor-design&quot;&gt;Poor Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wall Switch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have this thing with switches where I don’t know when it is on or off. At the apartment I live in I have a wall switch (see Fig. 4). The wall switch has the switches for the Cooker, Laundry Machine, Fan and Oven. The big issue is you cannot tell which switch is for which appliance without actually switching it on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Dieter Rams listed in his design principles a design should be unobtrusive, it makes the product understandable but this wall switch fails miserably by those design principles. Most people will blame themselves saying “I don’t know how it works”. A good design should eliminate the need for that and should automatically inform the users what each switch does. This is a small wall switch imagine an auditorium having such, it would be a complete disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are two ways this problem can be fixed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leaving the switch on the appliances&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Labelling each switch
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/wallswitch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a wall switch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 4 A Switch Wall&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faucets with Handle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wherever I step into a public restroom and I see they have a faucet with a handle(see Fig. 5) I shrug. This is a personal pet peeve of mine. For example, someone takes a poo and wants to wash their hands they have to touch the handle, wash their hands and use the same hand to close the faucet, this makes no sense at all. The handle  gets dirtier with each use, it is a bacteria transfer station, a  total mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/faucetsjpg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a faucet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 5 A Faucet with Handle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This product is not designed thoroughly down to the last detail and lacks usefulness. And also what I do in this situation is leave the restroom or when I’m pressed I use tissue paper to move the handle which makes the product not environmentally friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple solution to this product is using a faucet that uses a sensor (see Fig. 6).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/faucetswithsensor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a faucet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 6 Faucet with Sensor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snapchat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snapchat is a mobile phone app that started as an app that allows users to exchange photos that disappear. With time Snapchat kept adding features that made the app lose most of its user base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These features they added include text messaging, phone calls, video calls and also building a gaming platform(see Fig 7) into the app. The term used for this, is called “feature creeping”. Feature creeping is the excessive ongoing expansion or addition of new features to a product, especially in computer software, video games and consumer and business electronics. These extra features go beyond the basic function of the product and can result in software bloat and over-complication, rather than simple design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good design makes a product understandable, Snapchat design is not that. A new user coming to use Snapchat will be overwhelmed by the features the app provides, which makes the application difficult to understand and use. The features in the app are too much for the user it makes it obtrusive of the user only wants to user Snapchat for snapchatting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gamingsnap.png&quot; alt=&quot;gaming platform&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 7 Snapchats Gaming Platform&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exercise introduced me to the 10 Principles for Good Design and allowed me to use it to critically analyse products in terms of their design. The products on these write ups are items I use in my daily life. I leveraged this opportunity to understand their underlining design on why they look the way they do and their features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand a product, you need to go back to the past and read the history behind it. History tells you what shaped it what it is and the reason for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, a good or poor design depends on the users intuition. It is all subjective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/dieter-rams-10-principles-of-good-design-e7790cc983e9&quot;&gt;https://hackernoon.com/dieter-rams-10-principles-of-good-design-e7790cc983e9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_creep&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_creep&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/snapchat-losing-popularity-social-media-app-facebook-tiktok-2019-1?r=US&amp;amp;IR=T&quot;&gt;https://www.businessinsider.com/snapchat-losing-popularity-social-media-app-facebook-tiktok-2019-1?r=US&amp;amp;IR=T&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.interaction-design.org/literature/article/dieter-rams-10-timeless-commandments-for-good-design&quot;&gt;https://www.interaction-design.org/literature/article/dieter-rams-10-timeless-commandments-for-good-design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://totebagfactory.com/blogs/news/history-of-the-tote-bag&quot;&gt;https://totebagfactory.com/blogs/news/history-of-the-tote-bag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/Good-and-Poor-Design</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/Good-and-Poor-Design</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello 👋</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello?&lt;/strong&gt; My name is Salim Abubakar, I’m currently studying Design, Innovation and Brand Management at University for the Creative Arts. This blog is holding my thought process for my university work as a journal for my journey through my degree. I’ll also share other things that interest me on this blog especially Software Engineering and Digital Design. I studied Software Engineering in my undergraduate degree. My interest heavily relies on how digital products can be improved through design, making the User Interface and User Experience more aesthetically pleasing and intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 05:43:48 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/Hello</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/Hello</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
