<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts &amp; Ideas</title>
    <description>Mostly university work, design and programming
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 05:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 05:08:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Manifesto: Principles for Digital Design 💊</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;These are the design principles I belive in and follow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put the user first&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use a design system&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design system speeds up work, saves time and promotes consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prototyping is your best friend&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add personality to your work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital design has fall into a mess, where every websites, every app looks the same. Go on &lt;a href=&quot;http://behance.com&quot;&gt;behance.com&lt;/a&gt; or dribbble all the digital deisgn look the same, with slight changes to the colour. Design should have personality and character like fashion, when you use a digital product you should have a clue who designed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the humane design guideline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The humane design guideline is a resource that provides guidance for designing ethically humane digital products through patterns focused on user well-being. With the growth in mobile technology where time and attention is an increasingly scarce resource. Instead of making us better as humans. It is exploiting out phsycolosgical vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As designers, we play a vital role in that space. It is our duty to build products that serve us not harm us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 04:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/01/Manifesto</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/01/Manifesto</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brand You: M&amp;S Food 🛒</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop&quot;&gt;Workshop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HOW ARE YOU DEFINED THROUGH THE BRANDS THAT YOU USE?, was the question asked in the “Brand You” workshop. The workshop is about understanding brands you patronage and asking yourself why you do so. The workshop started by splitting us into groups of 4 and individually listing out all the brands we buy into. And how they define my life as human being and a consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;question&quot;&gt;Question&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the task for 30 minutes, and then produce one visual to present your
overall findings to the group. Following this form groups and each group is to
select one brand from those presented to analyse with a view to revealing the
core elements of the brand, using the framework and tools provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I listed out several brands I buy into, then it transformed it into different categories such as clothing brands, apps, etc. But the main point of this workshop is it to pick one from the list and break it down into product/service benefits, positioning, attributes, mission, vision and values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing only one from the list was a daunting task. I decided to use M&amp;amp;S Food, the food branch of M&amp;amp;S. Marks and Spencer Group plc (commonly abbreviated as M&amp;amp;S or colloquially Marks and Sparks) is a major British multinational retailer with headquarters in Westminster, London that specialises in selling high quality clothing, home products and food products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-ms-food&quot;&gt;Why M&amp;amp;S Food?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past 3 years I shop for groceries and household items from Tesco, Asda and Coop, I recently moved to London and the nearest grocery store to me is M&amp;amp;S Food. I decided to go in and shop, the first thing that captured my attention outside was the a big banner talking about M&amp;amp;S promises to sustainability(see Fig. 1 &amp;amp; 2). I stepped into the store and I was set aback by their service, cleanliness, products and promise on sustainability. I felt joyous inside the shop, I have never felt that feeling in any supermarket chain. It was an elevated experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/by_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sustainibility&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig.  1 Sustainibility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/by_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sustainibility&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig.  2 Sustainibility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;product--service-benefit&quot;&gt;Product / Service Benefit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I understand by product benefit as a customer is the reason why I buy their products and the uniqueness that sets it apart from the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a new loyal customer of M&amp;amp;S food the benefit I get from the brand is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Quality&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The main reason I buy into this brand is the quality of their products. As reported in the 2018 Brand Loyalty Index by Sodexo Engage M&amp;amp;S tops the list with customer saying they are loyal to the company because of its high quality products(Ainsworth, 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Value for Money&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;M&amp;amp;S is a Premium Brand and by that I mean they give their customers the best features at the best value. They operate with a close to one ratio of functionality and price. So since they are providing the best features and quality, consumers pay them high price for that. They also reinforce this feeling of premium by advertisement on their bags when you shop (see Fig. 3). Even though their prices are higher than tesco, sainsburys, asda, lidl/adl, etc I’m still happy to patronise them.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/by_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;M&amp;amp;S Food Bag&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Fig. 3 M&amp;amp;S Food Bag&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make a Difference&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;M&amp;amp;S is the first and only neutral carbon company. Plan A is an ethical programme M&amp;amp;S lauched in 2007 to tackles both today’s and tomorrow’s sustainable retail challenge(&lt;a href=&quot;http://global.marksandspencer.com/&quot;&gt;Global.marksandspencer.com&lt;/a&gt;, 2020).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;positioning--attributes&quot;&gt;Positioning / Attributes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brand sells food and household items. They package most of their products with paper instead of plastics, which makes their presentation look better and is part of their sustainability goal. The way products are presented play a vital role on how consumers behave towards it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are different brands competing in this market. Tesco, Sainsburys, Coop, Aldi/Lidl and Waitrose. It is a well known fact M&amp;amp;S Food is far superior in quality compared to Tesco, Sainsburys, Coop and Aldi/Lid and it is seen from their premium price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M&amp;amp;S Food main competitor is Waitrose, which also positions itself the same way as M&amp;amp;S providing high quality products with the same premium price. And targeting the same group people M&amp;amp;S Food does. The difference between the two is M&amp;amp;S own-brand items have better quality and their food is better seasoned compared to Waitrose(this sentence is backed-up by my personal experience).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While working on this workshop I stumbled upon several forums discussing about “which one is posher  Waitrose vs M&amp;amp;S Food and the result is always M&amp;amp;S Food wining, a fine detail I wanted to add and you could search it up also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mission--vision&quot;&gt;Mission / Vision&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M&amp;amp;S value is highly invested into making their customers feel premium and branding themselves as a premium line for products and services. One of the keys to the development of Marks &amp;amp; Spencer over the years has been the ability of the brand to meet the ever-changing needs of a broad customer base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brand’s ‘vision’ is to provide a standard against which its competitors may be measured, from customer experience, to care for the environment and community and to the working environment for employees. This can backed-up by their promise to sustainability and high quality products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;values&quot;&gt;Values&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core brand values of quality, value, service, innovation and trust have consistently remained the cornerstones of the Marks &amp;amp; Spencer proposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M&amp;amp;S as a brand has existed for over 100 years, adapting and evolving over time. This long-time heritage helps them to understand their broad customer bases ever-changing needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a consumer you are defined through the brands you buy into for these reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They make connection with you and make you feel special.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They project what you stand for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ainsworth, P. (2018). Brand Loyalty Index: M&amp;amp;S Voted Customers’ Favourite Supermarket. [online] &lt;a href=&quot;http://cxm.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Cxm.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cxm.co.uk/brand-loyalty-index-ms-voted-customers-favourite-supermarket/&quot;&gt;https://cxm.co.uk/brand-loyalty-index-ms-voted-customers-favourite-supermarket/&lt;/a&gt; [Accessed 24 Jan. 2020].&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://global.marksandspencer.com/&quot;&gt;Global.marksandspencer.com&lt;/a&gt;. (2020). Plan A. [online] Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://global.marksandspencer.com/plan-a/&quot;&gt;https://global.marksandspencer.com/plan-a/&lt;/a&gt; [Accessed 24 Jan. 2020].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 04:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/12/Brand-You</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/12/Brand-You</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Archive Research: Review 📖</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received an underwhelming response for my presentation on the archive brief. Which you can find here. I decided to find the cause and learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interpretation&quot;&gt;Interpretation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem was not from time management. I booked and viewed the archive of my choice early enough to produce an interesting and meaningful presentation. So, I had enough time to work on this brief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, the significant issue is that maybe the tutors didn’t understand what I was trying to convey because of the method I used. I try to keep my presentations short and precise. It helps to hold the listener’s attention(Atherton, 2009). I believe the system I used for my presentation is the cause for the underwhelming feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the original archive I was meant to view didn’t spark any ideas on how to carry the materials into a further study. I had to change the materials of the archive when I went to view the materials. I believe reading up about the archive before viewing could have prevented this issue. I decided to view and observe the materials without reading up about it to avoid any preconceived idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get to the bottom of this problem I showed and asked my course-mates about my presentation. I asked them what their thoughts were about it and if they had any idea why the tutors were not content with my presentation. I received a different response from each person and took notes of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the responses I received:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I think it was too short”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“You didn’t describe clearly why you picked the subject and the archive”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘You assumed everybody knew/knows bauhaus design”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“The images in one slide was too cluttered to understand”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“You were speaking a bit fast”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After gathering these responses I sat down and viewed my presentation slides and tried to make a correlation. See fig 1. which shows the cluttered images on the slide, I used a transition for each image, they didn’t appear together at once. It is still valid feedback because I could have done better, for example using two images per slide. The presentation is short was to hold the listeners’ attention as stated before. I didn’t have a content page and that caused me to skip valuable explanations for why I chose the archive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/r.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cluttered Image Slide&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 1 Cluttered Image Slide&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It later became clear to me I used a conference-style presentation instead of a project style. I paid more attention thinking I only have audience and forgetting it is a project and I will be under scrutiny. It happened as a result of the tips I saw on the internet which were not for project-based presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;outcome&quot;&gt;Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most Importantly, I have learned that peer feedback is an important aspect of learning. Peer feedback means that feedback is given by one student to another, through comments made on each other work, behaviour or performances(Liu and Carless, 2006). Peer feedback can help students develop that all-important appreciation of what counts as high-quality work in the discipline or subject area (Sadler, 1989), while at the same time enabling them ‘to take an active role in the management of their learning(Liu and Carless, 2006). I’m in a University environment where sharing and learning together is part of it. I could have easily asked a course-mate to peer review my presentation and doing that could have eliminated the issue I faced when presenting my results. I would have received feedback to improve or change my presentation slides. Having analysed and discussed the cause of the problem I now know the cause and solution to the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this brief was the most challenging one I have done so far and it introduced me to the value of peer feedback. Looking back, I believe my results for the archive brief would have been way better if I had a better presentation slide. I learned a lot from how to undertake archival research and making notes of my observations and thoughts. Also thinking beyond the scope of the research and material I viewed and finding a way to carry it further into a useful study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to edit my slide using the feedback I received and you can find it here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Atherton, C. (2009). When giving presentations, the only rule that matters is the rule of attention. [online] Finite Attention Span. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://finiteattentionspan.wordpress.com/2009/11/02/the-only-rule-about-giving-presentations-that-matters-is-the-rule-of-attention/&quot;&gt;https://finiteattentionspan.wordpress.com/2009/11/02/the-only-rule-about-giving-presentations-that-matters-is-the-rule-of-attention/&lt;/a&gt; [Accessed 12 Dec. 2019].&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sadler, D. R. (1989). Formative Assessment and the Design of Instructional Systems. Instructional Science, 18, 119-144.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liu, N. and Carless, D. (2006). Peer feedback: the learning element of peer assessment. Teaching in Higher Education, 11(3), pp.279-290.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 04:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/12/Archive-Research-Review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/12/Archive-Research-Review</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Love Challenge: Let’s Get Coding ⌨️</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;challenge&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about ways that you can ‘spread the love’ in the community by making people happy to spend time helping their neighbours. The task is for the social services division of Epsom and Ewell council, they are trying to save money by getting the community to help each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/keyboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;Keyboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 1 Keyboard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge is a group work, we were 3 in our group. The first thing we did as a group was to search for the Epsom and Ewell services division and see what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, we had to understand what “spread the love” means to have a clear vision of what we should do for the community. “spread the love” is about helping others. The good thing about helping others is it makes you happy and creates safety for you (Marie Hartwell-Walker, 2020). This simple understanding of “spread the love” in the community gave us an idea on what to work with. The idea is helping is not only beneficial for them but also you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used this idea of “spread the love” to brainstorm as team and generate different ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Story Time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Physical Activitives e.g dancing, hiking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one idea that remained after scrutiny is the one to teach kids how to code, the programme is mainly for kids but old people can also join in the fun. The idea is to bring kids together to learn how to develop their skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;developing-idea&quot;&gt;Developing Idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this part, we take the idea and develop it into a practical idea that can benefit the community taking into consideration different factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cost&quot;&gt;Cost&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University has a partnership with Epsom and Ewell Council which allows members of the community during the weekend to come to the university to learn and socialise. Our idea fits in perfectly when parents come they can drop their kids or join them to take part in the programme. This programme is not going to cost the council a dime. The University has computers available which the programme will use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;target&quot;&gt;Target&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The target group for this social service programme is for young kids and old people. Our program is designed mainly for young kids but also any other person can take the advantage to learn something useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;volunteering&quot;&gt;Volunteering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should people volunteer to teach people how to code?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Opportunity to learn new skills&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gain real-world experience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be part of a community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boost your career&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learning&quot;&gt;Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to equip people with coding and communicating skills. The syllabus will be designed with kids in mind. The syllabus will start from foundational basic up to where the participants can be able to apply their new skills to solve their own and community problem through coding or problem-solving. Other skills are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Logical Thinking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creativity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Math Skills&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Problem-solving skills&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Innovation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Computer Literacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ad-campaign&quot;&gt;Ad Campaign&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a way to promote the programme and make people attend we had to find a way to make kids come. When kids hear it is going to be about education, they might not be interested. We decided to build an Ad Campaign around making their dreams come true. The idea came from the LEGO 2017 ad campaign that encourages kids to build their future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the tagline “create your dreams” flyers will be designed to tell the kids they will learn how to create their video games, apps and websites. Using this idea kid will be inspired to create their dreams and make them attend the programme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, this challenge was engaging and fulfilling within a short period of time we were able to brainstorm and generate ideas. And also narrow the ideas into one and how can we possibly make it happen. Researching about the social services what they offer and how our idea will be different. Thinking about why people should volunteer and how to get kids to join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, having done several challenges and briefs in group I feel now I tend to work better in a group by giving peer reviews and communicating better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stern, C. (2020). Lego’s latest campaign is super cute. [online] Mail Online. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-4672790/Lego-s-new-campaign-urges-kids-build-future.html&quot;&gt;https://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-4672790/Lego-s-new-campaign-urges-kids-build-future.html&lt;/a&gt; [Accessed 18 Dec. 2019].&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marie Hartwell-Walker, E. (2020). 6 Reasons to Spread the Love. [online] Psych Central. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://psychcentral.com/lib/6-reasons-to-spread-the-love/&quot;&gt;https://psychcentral.com/lib/6-reasons-to-spread-the-love/&lt;/a&gt; [Accessed 18 Dec. 2019].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 04:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/12/Love-Challenge</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/12/Love-Challenge</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Archive Research: Posters for London Underground 🖼️</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I viewed  Hans Schleger corporate exhibition and graphic designer : papers archive at V&amp;amp;A museum in London. Hans Schleger is a prolific Graphic Designer from Germany who was heavily influenced by the Bauhaus Design School (Black, 2012. The archive consisted of posters, advertising, corporate identity and packaging designs Schleger worked on. For my project I focused on the posters designed for London Underground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I examined 8 posters commissioned between 1935-1947. The posters have different themes associated with them. In 1935 Schleger was commissioned to produce a pair of posters on the theme ‘The Underground Gets You There’ with the objective of promoting the improving reliability of Underground services (see Fig. 1 &amp;amp; 2). In 1943, commissioned him to produce a poster series urging the public to take more care while travelling during the WWII blackout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A poster in its most basic form is a temporary promotion of an idea, product or event put up in a public space for mass consumption(Lippert, 2017). Posters are designed to be eye-catching and informative to makes the viewer understand and digest the message within seconds. Using this definition and understanding I designed questions to help me note down my observations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does it have a message printed on it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are there questions or instructions?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the main colours used?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the poster try to persuade mainly through words, visuals, or both equally?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was happening at the time in history this poster was created?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why was it created?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1935&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Service” poster (left side of pair)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/plu_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Service&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 1 Service&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“On Time” poster (right side of pair)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/plu_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On Time&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 2 On Time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does it have a message printed on it?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Service On Time!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are there questions or instructions?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;No, It is informative&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the main colours used?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Red, Black and Grey&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does the poster try to persuade mainly through words, visuals, or both equally?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Both Equally&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What was happening at the time in history this poster was created?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The objective of promoting the improving reliability of Underground services.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why was it created?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The objective of promoting the improving reliability of Underground services.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1937&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poster of “Safety Week”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/plu_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Safety Work&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 3 Safety Work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does it have a message printed on it?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Safety Work&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are there questions or instructions?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;NO&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the main colours used?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Red, Black&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does the poster try to persuade mainly through words, visuals, or both equally?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Visuals&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was happening at the time in history this poster was created?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why was it created?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;As a safety awareness campaign&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who do you think is the intended audience?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;London Underground users&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1938&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To Chorley Wood” poster (one of a pair)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/plu_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chorley Wood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 4 Chorley Wood&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does it have a message printed on it?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Cheap tickets on Easter&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are there questions or instructions?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;NO&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the main colours used?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Red, Green, Yellow&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does the poster try to persuade mainly through words, visuals, or both equally?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;NO&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was happening at the time in history this poster was created?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why was it created?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Inform people about Easter discount and new routes&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1943&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the Blackout, before you alight make sure the train is
in the station. Look for platform” poster&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/plu_5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;In The Blackout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 5 In The Blackout&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does it have a message printed on it?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Before you alight make sure the train is in the station. Look for platform&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are there questions or instructions?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the main colours used?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Black, Red&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does the poster try to persuade mainly through words, visuals, or both equally?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Both Equally&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What was happening at the time in history this poster was created?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;During WWII&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why was it created?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Promote ways of surviving a blackout compelled by bombing raids during WWII&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1946&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Extension Central line” poster with key design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/plu_6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Extension Central Line&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 6 Extension Central Line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does it have a message printed on it?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Extension of Central Line opening on Dec 4&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are there questions or instructions?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;No&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the main colours used?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Red, Blue&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does the poster try to persuade mainly through words, visuals, or both equally?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Both equally&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was happening at the time in history this poster was created?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why was it created?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Inform people about the new routes opening on Central Line&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1947&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Central line Eastern extension” poster (right side of pair)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/plu_7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Central Line Eastern Extension&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 7 Central Line Eastern Extension&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does it have a message printed on it?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Extension of Central Line opening on May 5&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are there questions or instructions?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;No&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the main colours used?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Red, Black&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does the poster try to persuade mainly through words, visuals, or both equally?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Both equally&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was happening at the time in history this poster was created?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why was it created?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Inform people about the new routes opening on Central Line&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;findings--thoughts&quot;&gt;Findings &amp;amp; Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing these posters to contemporary light you can see the form posters take now has changed drastically(see Fig. 8). There is no more art involved in poster design. I think the major cause of the shift in poster design for London Underground is the advancement in technology. It is now possible to print high-quality posters with pictures. And now advertisement screens allow the rotation of poster ads per screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prefer the use of art in poster design in London Underground because through the expressiveness of Graphic Design artist tell better stories and trigger emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/plu_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Poster&quot; /&gt;
Fig. 8 Modern Poster&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed a pattern all the posters had a red colour on them. I decided to find the reason why they have a red colour. I think Hans used the colour red for emphasis. It helps him to capture the viewer’s attention to that bit of the poster. As you can see all the posters except fig. 4, the part coloured red is the most important part of the poster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collection of posters designed for London Underground is one pit stop to discover Graphic Design trend without any gaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;further-study&quot;&gt;Further Study&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brief for this project stated the final outcome for the brief is finding a way to yield a useful study to take archive research brief further.  Being a software engineer with interest into digital design and I had an idea/thought on how to carry this further as a study. The ideas is to create a Information Visualisation of all the posters designed from the first commissioned poster till date for London Underground. Information Visualisation, the art of representing data in a way that it is easy to understand and to manipulate, can help us make sense of information and thus make it useful in our lives (The Interaction Design Foundation, 2019).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea came from the fact London Underground has a cult following. The followers are really into anything London Underground. The Information Visualisation is not only for fans of London Underground but also for people into design to see the growth in how poster design has evolved, changed and shaped the world we live now. And I want people to see what I have seen because it is amazing work. It will also be a place of preserving art for the next generation and more. Using Information Visualisation an experience can be designed with these posters. The visualisation will allow people to explore and see the change, progress, design influence, message, typography and journey of posters in London Underground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;presentation&quot;&gt;Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I edited my presentation in a way to tell a narrative. The narrative starts from how I stumbled on this archive, my process, findings, thoughts and how to take this archive research brief further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find it here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This archive research brief introduced me to something different. I have never been to an archive nor recorded my observations and thoughts through content analysis. The most important thing I learned is the process of uncovering the interesting bits of the posters and shedding light on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black, J. (2012). For the People’s Good: Hans Schleger (1898–1976), Poster Design and British National Identity, 1935–60. Visual Culture in Britain, 13(2), pp.169-190.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lippert, A. (2017). What is a poster? Poster House. [online] Poster House. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://posterhouse.org/what-is-a-poster/&quot;&gt;https://posterhouse.org/what-is-a-poster/&lt;/a&gt; [Accessed 21 Nov. 2019].&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Interaction Design Foundation. (2019). Information Visualization – A Brief Introduction. [online] Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.interaction-design.org/literature/article/information-visualization-a-brief-introduction&quot;&gt;https://www.interaction-design.org/literature/article/information-visualization-a-brief-introduction&lt;/a&gt; [Accessed 20 Nov. 2019].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 04:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/11/Archive-Research-Posters</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/11/Archive-Research-Posters</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Timeline: Journey into Streetwear 👟</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;brief&quot;&gt;Brief&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my Creative Thinking class I was tasked to design, create and present a personal timeline that highlights and evidences my own timeline of movers, shakers, innovators, critical thinkers and influencers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thought-process&quot;&gt;Thought Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first idea that came to me for this task is to breakdown my life in different stages from birth till now and recollect what I was into at that period from friends, music, movies and people around me to find my movers, shakers, innovators, critical thinkers and influencers. I soon realised that’s somewhat impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why not fashion?&lt;/strong&gt; The first thing most people do the first time they see or meet someone is look at what they are wearing. From what people wear you can have a clue what they are into and their influence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fashion-influence&quot;&gt;Fashion Influence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always been interested in fashion but I didn’t have the immediate stores around me in my country Nigeria, the only time I buy clothes is when I travel abroad. I was really limited by that fact. I moved to United Kingdom September 2015 to study. That was when I started investing and experimenting to find my style in clothes and shoes I wear. I started by looking into what was in trend in fashion and shopping pieces off high street brands like H&amp;amp;M, Topman, New Look, River Island and ASOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through time and experimentation I started to move closely into streetwear. Streetwear is a style of casual clothing which became global in the 1990s. It grew from Californian and skate culture, but also encompasses elements of hip-hop fashion, modern high fashion and haute couture (Marie Hartwell-Walker, 2020). In the recent years is experiencing and explosive popularity due a particular brand called Supreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking through the lens and looking through my photos, I designed an infographic of my journey into fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘Style is a way to say who you are without having to speak.’ – Rachel Zoe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Timeline.png&quot; alt=&quot;Timeline&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simpson, S. (2019). The Origins Of Streetwear: What Is It And How Do I Wear It?. [online] RebelsMarket Blog. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rebelsmarket.co.uk/blog/posts/the-origins-of-streetwear-what-is-it-and-how-do-i-wear-it&quot;&gt;https://www.rebelsmarket.co.uk/blog/posts/the-origins-of-streetwear-what-is-it-and-how-do-i-wear-it&lt;/a&gt; [Accessed 15 Dec. 2019].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 04:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/11/Timeline</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/11/Timeline</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Archive Research: Archive Choice 🗄️</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;brief&quot;&gt;Brief&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brief was given to me in my Research and Communication class, the brief requires me to explore an archive. The exploration is to understand how archive can be use to to yield material for use in research, through analysis, observation and wide variety of recording.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brief allows me to be flexible on what I want to research on. The research could be an interest or anything I can find my hands on. My first idea was to find a trainers archive. I love trainers it will be an opportunity to learn more about them and appreciate them more. I couldn’t find one in London. The only option was the Adidas shoe archive located in Germany. I had to drop this idea and find a new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second choice was any archive I could find relating to the Bauhaus design movement, Bauhaus was a design school in Germany founded by Walter Gropius. The school eventually morphed into its modern art movement characterised by its unique approach to architecture and design (Richman-Abdou, 2017). My choice for Bauhaus stems from my interest in their work and finding new insights into their work. I found one on the V&amp;amp;A archive website. I contacted V&amp;amp;A and booked an appointment to view the Thought &amp;amp; Idea - Bauhaus archive (See Fig. 1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ac_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Appointment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 1 Booking Appointment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before going to view the archive I had no prior knowledge about the archive, not even the owner, all I knew about the archive is it relates to Bauhaus design school. I decided to use this method to avoid any preconceived idea when observing the materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;archive&quot;&gt;Archive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The archive contained articles and notes about Bauhaus. I looked through each one carefully analysing and taking notes about them. The first material from the archive is a paper with pictures of the Bauhaus teachers(see Fig. 2) and some of their works which were quite interesting but after that. The rest of the archival materials where newspaper, prints and magazine cuts(see fig. 3) talking about Bauhaus works their exhibitions, school, teachers, etc. I quickly realised I can’t work with this archive to produce meaningful content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ac_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bauhaus Tearchers &amp;amp; Works&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 2 Bauhaus Tearchers &amp;amp; Works&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ac_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Prints&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fig. 3 Prints&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I was not able to create something from this archive is that the content of the archive are not related they are prints, magazines, texts, etc. There is no meaningful correlation to the contents, it was a mix and match contents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to check the archive details to understand why it exists and who owns it. The archive was owned by Hans Schleger an influential graphic designer from Germany, who did several commissioned work for London transport, helped modernised the London bus logo and several notable works(Black, 2012). The archive materials in this archive were very large it contained collections of articles, notes and press cuttings around various themes, used as research for Schleger’s work, and notes, correspondence and reference materials for specific projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While going through the archive page on V&amp;amp;As website I saw they had in store posters Hans Schleger designed for London Underground from 1936-1947. I decided to give it a try and see since this one has the same type of content in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to staff and asked for the posters designed by Hans for London Underground, she went into the room and came back out and said they are many I should pick the ones I want to see, immediately it came to my head to pick one from each year. After a few minutes, she came back with posters, upon viewing the posters a bulb came up in my head I was like I can surely work with this material. I went through them and snapped them on my phone so that I can take home and look at them more and create something meaningful out of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of finding an archive is quite long because it involves different steps. Which also add an interesting touch to the whole process knowing you are limited. I realised archive research is an activity that requires patience. You may not find exactly what you were looking for, but you may also find much more than you expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I feel like I should have done the research, read some published work before viewing the archive. It would have put me in a better position because I would have had a piece of background knowledge about what I’m viewing. It would have also saved my time and eliminated the back and forth I went through with the archivist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black, J. (2012). For the People’s Good: Hans Schleger (1898–1976), Poster Design and British National Identity, 1935–60. Visual Culture in Britain, 13(2), pp.169-190.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Richman-Abdou, K. (2017). Bauhaus: How the Avant-Garde Movement Transformed Modern Art. [online] My Modern Met. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://mymodernmet.com/what-is-bauhaus-art-movement/&quot;&gt;https://mymodernmet.com/what-is-bauhaus-art-movement/&lt;/a&gt; [Accessed 18 Nov. 2019].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 04:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/11/Archive-Research-Archive-Choice</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/11/Archive-Research-Archive-Choice</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Cut: Review 📚</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-in-a-group&quot;&gt;Working in a Group&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of working in a group is to increase performance and productivity by planning and problem solving while collectively working together.
There are great advantages to working in a group. I alone can only think of so many ideas, but a group of 5 individuals discussing ideas between each other can think of countless ideas. Bouncing concepts off of one another and collectively coming together to select the best one, then expanding on that concept is really what group work is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;presentation&quot;&gt;Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After presenting our presentation for the brief, the tutor reinstated the objective of the brief. The tutor said the objective of the brief is to see the progress of researching and negotiating as a team together. Which our presentation was not about, our presentation was about finding a solution for a problem which is almost the opposite of the objective for the brief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach we used as a team was initiated by one member of the group. The group member said this was the approach they used for this type of project. I feel the problem started here because none of us questioned the approach or critically thought about it. Is it the right way for this project? as a team, we all went with the flow and shared the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, our group achieved a semi-successful outcome, the tutor said he liked our vlog and stop motion video we created for the project. Our failure arose from us not having a clear understanding of the brief and questioning the rationale behind the person that suggested the methodology for the brief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward when I’m working in a group I’ll make sure as a team we go through the brief together to draw a complete understanding of what we are undertaking and objectives before brainstorming . for ideas and starting the work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 04:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/11/First-Cut-Review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/11/First-Cut-Review</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>International Pedagogy: How far? 📍</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;brief&quot;&gt;Brief&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;International Pedagogy was the first challenge I was given in my Research and Communication class. The challenge is to edit and present to members of our new cohort with simple phrases and/or actions and information to teach them about what “you” think they need to know about where you are from. The presentation should not be seen from a tourist perspective but a personal perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brief has a paragraph stating “key words and phrases, cultural considerations, etiquette and how to be streetwise”. I started my work by looking at the paragraph and listing all the possible ways I could go with my presentation. I picked each theme and made a list of what I could explore using that theme. I called my mum and asked her to tell me things only Nigerians can relate to. I texted my friends and asked them about it. And my personal experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;words-and-phrases&quot;&gt;Words and Phrases&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I dive into this theme I need to give background knowledge about Nigerian Pidgin Language. Pidgin language is a language that has developed from a mixture of two languages. It is used as a way of communicating by people who do not speak each other’s languages (Pidgin, n.d). Nigerian Pidgin is an English based pidgin language spoken in every part of Nigeria, it is sort of a lingua franca in Nigeria. Nigerian Pidgin is used in informal conversations. Nigerian Pidgin is so popular Google Search has an interface for it and a lot of News outlets like BBC also do their news in the slang. An example of Nigerian Pidgin is “I Dey” which means “I’m alright” in English. The brief has a paragraph stating “key words and phrases, cultural considerations, etiquette and how to be streetwise”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most popular phrase in Nigerian Pidgin is “How far?”. “How far?” has different meanings depending on the context. In most contexts, it is a simple informal greeting that’s best used with people you know. It means “How is everything”, if someone asks you “How far?” in Nigeria they are not referring to your journey to meet them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are many other Nigerian Pidgins but I cannot go through of all of them because there is as many words or phrases as a dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cultural-considerations&quot;&gt;Cultural Considerations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The northern part of Nigeria is heavily influenced by Islam. The cultural considerations follow mostly Islamic /Arab culture. Where women and women are separated in social activities unless they are siblings or married.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wedding Fatiha [Daurin Aure]&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Wedding from where I come from is a whole week event starting with a wedding Fatiha(Islamic marriage) and ending with the main wedding reception.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Here are the lists of events that take place in order:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Kayan Lefe
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The grooms’ side of the family shop for the bride. The items include but are not limited to shoes, bags, clothes, underwear, perfumes, cash, etc&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wedding Fatiha [Daurin Aure]
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This is the most significant part of the wedding. A religious priest is invited to make the wedding official. The event takes place at the mosque or brides house with guests invited. As opposed to what obtains in many other cultures, in the Hausa culture it is a representative from the groom and bride’s family usually does the exchange of vows and not the bride and groom.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wuni [Sa lalle]
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This is event is strictly for ladies, the brides family, friends and the grooms family. The event takes place in the brides family home. A mixture of traditional henna is made and used to make beautiful designs on the brides’ palms, hands and feet. Friends and families get henna designs on their bodies also.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Kamun Amariya
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;It is a playful event where the grooms family goes to the brides family home to convince and negotiate with them to allow them to take their daughter, thus making her part of the grooms family.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Kai Amariya
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This is where family and friends escort the bride to her matrimonial home, to be well received by the groom’s family. It is followed by prayers and advice from family and friends. It ends with entertainment, food and music for the family and guest.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;etiquette&quot;&gt;Etiquette&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nigerian etiquette is different from western etiquette, some westerners might call it absurd. To compile the list for my presentation I had to research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Physical/Body Contact&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;In this part of the world called Nigeria physical contact is seen as a very normal activity, for example when someone is trying to call your name, get your attention or simply when having a conversation they can touch you. To outsiders, they’ll find this odd because of the invasion of personal space.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Greeting&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Exchange of greeting cannot be rushed, it is seen as rude behaviour. You must take the time to ask about the person’s health, the health of their family, or other social niceties. That sounds quite normal but the problem is if you see the same person the next day you have to do it all over again. Also when greeting someone much older, it is a sign of respect and deference to bow the head.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Age&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Old age in Nigeria is an accomplishment. Old people are given utmost respect and cannot be disrespected in any way even if they are wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Left Hand is a Taboo&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Avoid greeting, giving or receiving objects or handling money or food with your left hand. It is seen as disrespectful and disgusting to greet, eat, handover or collect things from others with a left hand.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Time&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;There is a concept of time called “Nigerian Time” which is a concept where things rarely start on time, appointments are not usually made, interruptions are frequent, and one can expect to wait for things to happen. When someone tells you an event is starting at 7 pm it means it’ll start at 9 pm or 10 pm. And also it is a way of showing high standards by making the person wait.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;presentation&quot;&gt;Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I titled my presentation “How Far?” to draw the attention of my audience by telling them I’ll explain the meaning of the title at the end of the presentation. I did that to hold the listeners attention. For the presentation since none of my listeners are from where I come from, I tried to focus on the things that are completely normal in Nigeria but are absurd to people from not that part of the world. I re-edited my research and created a 5 minutes presentation, you can find &lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.cambridge.org/&quot;&gt;Dictionary.cambridge.org&lt;/a&gt;. (2019). PIDGIN  meaning in the Cambridge English Dictionary. [online] Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://dictionary.cambridge.org/dictionary/english/pidgin&quot;&gt;https://dictionary.cambridge.org/dictionary/english/pidgin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 05:43:48 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/International-Pedagogy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/International-Pedagogy</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Visual Statistics: Let's Talk 📷</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Brief&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 05:43:48 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/Visual-Statistics</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/Visual-Statistics</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
